// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " A student moves along the boundary of a square field of side 10 In in 40 see. If he started from one of the corners of the square what will be the magnitude of displacement of the student at the end of 2 minutes and 20 seconds from his initial position?",
    answer: "l0√2 m.",
    options: [
      "10m.",
      "l0√2 m.",
      "40m.",
      "30m."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Determine the torque due to a force   → F  = 2i - 3j + 4k N acting at a point   →  r = 3i + 2j + 3k about the origin?",
    answer: "17i + 6j - 13k",
    options: [
      " 6i - 6j + 12k",
      "-6i + 6j + 12k",
      "17i + 6j - 13k",
      "-17i + 6j + 13k"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "An airplane travelled from Addis Ababa to Mekele, 780km, in 45 minutes. What was its average speed?",
    answer: "1040 km/hr",
    options: [
      "0.28 m/sec",
      "1040 km/hr",
      "17.3 m/min",
      "585 km/hr"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "An example of a body moving with constant speed but still accelerating is:",
    answer: "A body moving in a circular path",
    options: [
      " A body moving on a straight road",
      "A body moving on a straight railway track",
      "A body moving in a circular path",
      "A body moving in a circular path"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " The area under a force versus distance graph represents:",
    answer:  "work done.",
    options: [
      "acceleration",
      "the change in energy.",
      "the change in momentum.",
      "work done."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A net external non zero force acts on a particle that is moving along a straight line. Which one of the following statements is correct? ",
    answer: "Both the Velocity and the kinetic energy of the particle are changing.",
    options: [
      "The velocity, but not the kinetic energy, of the particle is changing.",
      "Both the Velocity and the kinetic energy of the particle are changing.",
      "The kinetic energy, but not the Velocity, of the particle is changing.",
      "The momentum is conserved."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The rotational analogue of mass is:",
    answer:  " moment of inertia.",
    options: [
      " moment of inertia.",
      "torque.",
      "angular momentum.",
      "angular acceleration."
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "A device for transforming heat energy to mechanical energy is referred to as: ",
    answer: "engine",
    options: [
      "transformer.",
      "refrigerant",
      " generator",
      "engine"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The number of joules of heat energy required to raise the temperature of a body by l K is:",
    answer: "Heat capacity.",
    options: [
      "Heat capacity.",
      "Specific heat capacity.",
      "Expansion coefficient.",
      "Calorific value."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The definition of Young's Modulus is given by: ",
    answer: "ratio of stress to strain.",
    options: [
      " force per unit area.",
      "ratio of strain to stress.",
      "ratio of stress to strain.",
      "force per unit elongation."
    ]
  },






];